# Bhawna Agarwal

Product Designer with 6 years of formal design education, and 8+ years of experience designing and shipping well-crafted, high-impact experiences in the industry. I specialize in applying product thinking to break down complex problems and craft helpful experiences.

# **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

#### Product Designer, Microsoft

April 2023-Present, Full-time | San Francisco Bay Area

- Lead designer for Microsoft's Al-powered help and support experiences
- Spearheaded design for 10+ experiences, reducing support costs for Microsoft
- Nurturing team growth by refining design processes and systems, and collaborating with senior leadership to strengthen design culture

#### Senior Product Designer, Wish

January 2021-April 2023, Full-time | San Francisco

- Led design for Shopping Cart, Checkout, and Payments. Redesigned the checkout experience which led to a -21.8% decline in the order refund rate.
- Influenced peers and executive leadership to prioritize user needs, driving alignment on key design decisions.
- Contributed to Wish's design system, improving consistency and scalability

#### **UX Designer, Microsoft Cloud**

April 2018-July 2019, Full-time | Hyderabad, India

- Sole designer responsible for Azure Backup, drove UX strategy and execution
- Partnered with 10+ product managers across multiple projects to enhance the Azure Backup service

#### UX Design Lead | Reported to CEO, Postman API Development

June 2016-December 2017, Full-time | Bangalore, India

- Early designer on the team—led UX strategy and execution, delivering
  6+ core projects in one year, driving productivity gains for 15M+ developers
- Proposed and secured executive buy-in for a more usable, extensible Data Editor component - a complex component in Postman's design system. Led the design process, ensuring seamless integration into the design system.
- Wore multiple hats beyond design—conducted research, provided customer support, authored product copy, and wrote feature marketing blog posts

#### **Earlier experiences**

- UX Designer, Housing.com, Full-time | June-December 2015
- UX Design Intern, HCII, Carnegie Mellon University | May-July 2014
- UX Design Intern, Robert Bosch | May-July 2013

# **EDUCATION**

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

Masters in UX Design

IIT Guwahati, India

Bachelor of Design with Minor in Computer Science

## **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Publications in ACM digital library as first author
- First position in OzCHI 2014 –
  International student design challenge
- S.N. Bose Scholar

## **SKILLS**

UX Research	Software
and Design	Figma
Contexual Inquiry	Sketch
User Interviews	Principle
Persona Building	Invision
Writing Job Stories	Photoshop
Info. Architecture	Illustrator
Heuristic Evaluation	InDesign
Usability Testing	Tableau
Wireframing	
Mobile Design	Coding
Visual/UI Design	HTML/ CSS
Prototyping	Javascript
UX Writing	jQuery
Storytelling	Python

## **PORTFOLIO**

bhawna2109.github.io/design